There's something I need to tell you.
我有件事没告诉你
I'm pregnant.
我怀孕了
I took
我拿那个
the pregnancy test
验孕棒也
as well.
验过了
I went to the hospital,
然后我也去医院
and had a blood test.
验了血
I... um...
我 我 我
The reason I didn't tell you
我没有告诉你的原因
is that I thought
是因为我想着
because of this baby,
如果有了这个孩子
our relationship
我们的关系
would definitely deepen.
势必会再进一步
But deep down,
但是我内心深处
I don't want us to be forced
是不想用这个孩子
to be tied together.
来绑架我们的感情
And I really don't want
然后我更不想
to use this child to tie you down.
用这个孩子来绑架你
You got it?
明白吗
I didn't know
我也
how to
不知道
explain this to you.
怎么跟你说
But
但是
your actions today
你今天的
make me feel
所作所为让我觉得
really secure.
特别地踏实
And I believe
然后
that you will
我想你会
become a partner
成为一个值得
that I can trust.
让我信任的伴侣
So,
所以
if possible,
如果有可能的话
should we take
我们要不要往前
a step forward?
一步试试
These
这些
are all my debit and credit cards.
都是我的银行卡
There are some savings in them.
里面有一些活期存款
You can take them out
你把它取出来
and keep them yourself.
收着
The large deposit certificates and
大额存单还有理财单据
financial documents are all at my place.
都放在我家
Later,
回头
let's transfer them to you.
都变更到你名下
And about my house...
还有我那套房子
Next week,
这样
we can take a day off
下周你请个假
to make
我们
your name added thereupon.
去办加名手续
Get it notarized.
公证一下
The property rights will be shared.
产权平分
If...
如果
I mean,
我是说如果
one day
哪一天
should I have an affair,
我做了对不起你的事情
all property rights would go to you.
产权全归你
I would leave with nothing.
我净身出户
It sounds like
这些听起来
you're giving me
好像是你的全部家当
all your possessions.
都给我了
Won't you
你不心疼
regret it?
不后悔吗
No,
不心疼
I won't.
也不后悔
Rao Jing,
饶静
I'll
我
definitely
一定
try my best
会努力地
be a good father.
做一个好爸爸
and also strive to
我更会努力地
be a good husband.
做一个好丈夫
I love you.
爱你
Not because of the child.
不是因为孩子
But because of you.
是因为你
Let's get married.
我们结婚吧
Let's do it.
结婚吧
But listen,
但是没有如果
you're not allowed to have any affairs.
你不能做对不起我的事
If any,
如果你做了
all your possessions
对不起我的事
will belong
你所有的家当
to me.
都是我的了
Can't sleep, huh?
是不是睡不着啊
I was just thinking.
我在想
The romance
静姐
of Jing and Fanggang has gone public.
跟小赵哥公开了
Will they...
那他们两个会不会
Zhao Fanggang
赵方刚
has already decided to resign.
已经决定离职了
There have been rumors in the bank
行里面最近一直在传
that Mr. Xing and Yao Jia
说邢总跟姚佳
are both going to face the penalty.
两个人都要被处罚
If our relationship
那我们两个的关系
gets exposed,
要是被发现了
will the two of us
会不会也两个人
also be punished?
都被处罚
Actually, whenever it involves
其实但凡涉及到
punishment,
处罚的话
there must be
一定是有
serious violations.
重大的违规行为
Issues of conduct
作风问题呢
are just the trigger.
其实也只是导火索
In recent years,
这几年他们两个人
they've colluded,
里应外合
lowering interest rates
放低利率
and reaching out to clients for benefits.
伸手向客户要好处
Such behavior
这种行为
is absolutely intolerable in the bank.
行里是不可能容忍的
However, we're
但是我们两个
in a completely different situation.
性质跟他们完全不一样
Right.
也对
I was so shocked that I got confused.
我都被吓糊涂了
Now that Jing's relationship
那小赵哥跟静姐的关系
was exposed,
被曝光了
as the supervisor,
你作为领导
you bear some responsibility.
也难辞其咎啊
If, at this moment,
如果这个时候
our relationship
我们两个的关系
was also exposed,
再被发现了
it would give the impression
那他们会认为
that S1
我们拓展一部
has serious issues.
作风有问题
They might think we're disregarding rules,
无视行里的行规
leading to a flurry of rumors.
就会有很多流言蜚语
Negative public sentiment could arise.
不好的舆论出现
It could
到时候
impact your chances for promotion.
就会影响到你晋升
Even
哪怕是
maintaining your current position
要保住现在的位置
might become quite challenging.
都很难了吧
Therefore,
所以说呀
trying to hide from this issue
这种问题
won't solve the problem.
躲躲藏藏是没有用的
We need to address it at its core.
我们得从根本上去解决
Tomorrow, I'll speak with the president
明天我去找一下行长
to check on the progress of the promotion.
追一下竞聘的进度
If I could successfully
如果说能成功
get transferred,
我顺利调走的话
it would benefit us,
不只是对我们
and also Rao Jing
对饶静和赵方刚
and Zhao Fanggang.
可能也有所帮助
That's true.
也是
To advance your career,
你要开疆拓土
you surely need someone to support.
总要有个人帮你才好
Having one of them on your team
他们俩呢其中一个人
would be beneficial.
过来对你都是有好处的
Well,
可是
whatever,
不管怎么说吧
I hope our wishes come true,
希望我们可以心想事成
and be able to
也可以
help Jing and Fanggang.
帮到静姐跟小赵哥他们
For now,
就是
let's just not worry too much.
先不想那么多了
Hello!
您好
Your food delivery is here.
您的外卖
Thank you so much.
谢谢啊辛苦了
No problem.
不辛苦
Why is the food delivery taking so long?
这外卖怎么还没到啊
Have you heard?
听说了吗
Mr. Zhao from S1 is resigning too.
一部的赵方刚也要辞职
[So many lovebirds]
这一对接一对的鸳鸯
[have been exposed.]
被爆出来
[No office romance rule]
行里又要重申
[will be reinforced again.]
家属回避政策
[Exactly.]
对呀 对呀
Our delivery is here.
外卖到了
Come on.
走
How are you holding up?
你怎么样啊
I'm doing alright,
还行吧
just feeling
就是
a bit anxious.
现在有点焦虑
I've been working for Dairui for 4 years.
我来代瑞四年了
If we
要是我们俩
were to be discovered,
万一真被发现了
one of us would have to leave.
必须要走一个
No matter who it is,
不管我们俩谁走
I would feel a sense of loss.
我都觉得舍不得
I also realize
也知道
that I won't find
再也找不到
a job more suited to me
比我们现在这份工作
than this one.
更适合自己的工作了吧
I'm just a bit concerned.
就是有点担心
I used to comfort you all the time.
以前我还总宽慰你
Right now,
现在
even I, as a receptionist,
就连我一个小前台
am able to sense
都能够感受到
the cold atmosphere
这栋大厦
in this building.
冰冷的氛围
All I can do is
我就只能
wish you all the luck
把我的好运都传给你
and pray that you won't get caught.
祈祷你们不会被发现
What are we having for lunch?
中午吃什么呀
Let's just order something simple.
要不咱俩对付一口吧
Sorry, I won't join you today.
今天可能不太行
I'm having lunch with my dad
我约了我爸吃饭
at the restaurant next door.
就在旁边的餐厅
Go ahead.
去吧
I'll buy you something good another time.
改天带你吃好吃的
Mr. Liu,
刘总 刘总
I understand completely.
我理解你的心情
However, the development of that land
不过那块地的开发呀
is not something that can be rushed.
真不是一朝一夕的事情
Yesterday, me and my team
昨天我带着团队
worked with your people until 4:00 a.m.
和你的人对到凌晨四点
Didn't they update you
他们方案
on their plans?
没有跟你同步吗
Alright, alright.
行了 行了
No need to worry.
你别着急
Let's talk about it this afternoon.
咱们下午见面聊
Alright?
好吧
Dad,
爸
what else would you like to order?
您还要吃什么呀
Help yourself.
你想吃什么随便点
I'm fine with anything.
我随便吃一口就行
Come on, put more thought into it.
那怎么能随便吃
[Yes.]
对
[Just call it]
就叫
["Star Residence Retirement Plan."]
星居养老计划
[580,000 square meters,]
五十八万平米
[a landmark complex.]
地标综合体
The only pure slab building in the area.
区域唯一的纯板楼
These points
这些点
need to be highlighted.
一定要突出强调
[Once the project proposal]
项目书
[is polished, just send it to me.]
润色好了之后发我
[I'll take a look]
我开会的间隙
during my meeting breaks.
抽空看一下
Has that loan not been repaid yet?
那笔贷款还没还哪
CC me on the email again.
邮件再抄送我一下
I'll approve it right away.
我马上批
Dad,
爸
here, have some water.
你喝口水吧
I never realized before
我以前都没发现
how much effort you put into your work.
原来您工作这么辛苦
Recently,
最近呢
I've saved up some money.
我攒了点钱
How about I treat you this time?
要不这顿我请你吧
Let you experience the feeling of
让你也享受一下
being treated to lunch
用女儿工资
by your daughter with her salary.
请客吃饭的感觉
That's so sweet!
这么贴心哪
Alright then.
行
In my fifties, I finally get to enjoy
年过半百我终于吃上
a meal my daughter is treating me to.
女儿请的饭了
But let's agree in advance.
不过我们提前说好
Could we keep the meal under 300?
这顿饭不能超过三百块
Otherwise, my salary won't be
不然我工资
enough to cover my living expenses.
就不够我花了
You called me here today,
你今天叫我来
and I was actually going to ask you
我正好想问问你
why you haven't used
你最近怎么不刷
the supplementary card I gave you.
我给你的副卡了
What's going on?
出什么事了吗
Nothing.
没出事
I'd like to
但是最近
try living
我想尝试
off my own salary
用我自己的工资
to support myself.
来养活我自己
What made you come up with
你怎么会有这种
such a strange idea?
突发奇想
Dad,
爸
you know very well that
你又不是不知道
I'd just buy
我之前啊
whatever I wanted
我就想要什么
without a second thought,
我就买什么
or even checking the price.
我也不看价格
I just
就
did whatever I pleased.
随心所欲地
But lately,
但最近啊
I've learned from Qi Yu that
我就从齐郁身上我发现
making money
好像赚钱
is really quite challenging.
真的挺不容易的
Aren't you the same?
你不也是吗
I used to think
我之前还觉得
that making money was easy for you.
你赚钱肯定老简单了
But the truth is
可是我现在才发现
that you even
你好像
got hard to sleep
也因为工作
or drink a glass of
晚上都没得觉睡
water
打个电话
because of work.
连喝口水的时间都没有
Recently,
最近
with my own salary,
我用我自己的工资啊
I've started to realize
我才发现
the true value
对钱也开始慢慢
of money.
有概念了
How much effort is needed to earn money,
劳动多少可以挣多少钱
or how much you earn
挣多少钱呢
determines how much you can spend.
可以用多少花多少
I'm very clear about this now.
我现在都老清楚了
Listen to me,
我跟你说啊
I want you to experience working
爸爸坚持让你工作
to get a better understanding
目的就是让你了解
of what money
钱是怎么回事
means.
要对它有个概念
After all, in your generation,
毕竟到了你们这一代啊
it's harder to save money than to make it.
守财比生财更难
Alright.
行了
I have seen
你的努力呢
your efforts.
爸爸看到了
Having a basic understanding
对钱有个基本的了解
is all that matters.
就可以了
I don't want to see you suffer.
我可不想我的女儿受苦
Look at what you've ordered.
你看看你点了些什么
My poor sweetie,
我可怜的女儿
spicy pig trotters is your favorite dish,
最喜欢的麻辣猪脚
and you wouldn't even order it.
都不舍得点
Dad,
爸
it costs
这份麻辣猪蹄
258 yuan.
二百五十八
My budget is only 300.
总共只有三百块
When spending money,
花钱还是得
it should be done wisely.
花在刀刃上吧
Excuse me.
服务员
May I help you?
您好
Spicy pig trotters, please.
给我们来一份麻辣猪脚
OK.
好
Dad!
爸
I've got that
这两百五十八
258 covered.
老爸来付
Let's enjoy ourselves!
敞开了吃
Dad, you're the best.
还是老爸对我好
Love you.
谢谢爸
It's tough to go from luxury to frugality.
由奢入俭难哪
Your way of saving
你这个节省法
makes life difficult for yourself.
为难自己的日子
The real challenges are still ahead.
还在后边呢
Sir.
叔叔
Hey.
来了
I wasn't expecting your call.
这么突然找我
Do you need something from me?
有什么事吗
Did you come
你今天过来
without telling Weiyi?
没告诉依依吧
No, I didn't.
没有
I just ran up the
我刚才跑那个
fire escape.
消防通道上来的
I heard you got accepted into the force.
我听说你考上警察了
Good.
不错
You're definitely someone
你也算是
who upholds their promise.
言出必行的人
As for me,
我呢
I also stand by my promises.
也是言而有信
I'll be fine with
你和依依的事情
you and Weiyi.
我就不再反对了
Thank you, sir.
谢谢叔叔
I'll make sure to take good care of her.
我一定会照顾好惟依的
You can count on me.
您放心
Can I?
是吗
She took me out
今天中午
for lunch earlier.
她请我出去吃饭
She wouldn't even order
连一盘自己喜欢的菜
a dish she likes.
都不舍得点
She is my only daughter.
我就这么一个女儿
Good for you!
行啊你小子啊
Did you pull a fast one on me?
跟我玩阴的是吧
Are you that desperate to become
为了新分行行长的位置
the president of the new branch?
你脸都不要了
It was you who leaked it
我老婆那里
to my wife, right?
是你捅出去的吧
You got all the clients
让所有的客户
to report me for taking kickbacks.
集体举报我吃回扣这事
You taught them to do that, didn't you?
是你教他们的吧
No, I didn't.
不是
Mr. Xing,
老邢
action betrays secrets.
要想人不知除非己莫为
You'll inevitably
小动作搞得多了
let your guard down
难免会有
if you pull too many tricks.
放松警惕的时候
When there're more people who dislike you,
看不惯你的人多了
naturally, someone will step up
自然就会有人站出来
to uphold justice.
主持正义
I also dedicate
这句话呢
this statement to you.
我同样也送给你
Ji Yuheng,
纪昱恒
you don't have to
你不承认这些事情
admit to all those tricks.
是你做得没关系
I've
我呢
prepared a
也为你准备了一份
parting gift for you.
临别赠礼
Enjoy.
还望你笑纳
Jingjing.
晶晶
Good morning.
早
XIaoning.
小涂
You okay?
你还好吧
Alright?
没事吧
What's going on?
什么意思呀
See for yourself, Xiaoning.
你自己看吧 小涂
What is it?
怎么了
It's OK.
没事
We'll get some air.
我们先出去一趟
Xiaoning,
筱柠
let's go.
走
What's the matter with you?
你怎么回事
You've kept this
这件事
from me the whole time.
从头到尾都瞒着我
Now it's all over the office.
现在行里都传遍啦
Your team just had a scandal,
你们部门刚爆出一对
and as a supervisor, you...
你这个领导又
Do you realize
你知不知道现在影响
how serious this is?
多恶劣
People are saying our conduct is improper
说我们作风不正
and management is chaotic.
管理混乱
Do you think you can still make
你说你这样还想当那个
the president of the branch?
集安分行的行长吗
Just pray that you won't be punished.
不给你处分就不错了
I'm sorry, sir.
对不起行长
I've let you down.
让您失望了
Regardless of what decision
不管行里这次做出
by the headquarters,
什么样的决定
I'll take full responsibility for it.
我来承担后果
Anyway, the two of us
反正我们俩
won't be able to work
也不可能留在
on the same team anymore.
同一个部门了
In the end, I'll be the one to leave.
到最后走的那个人
That's a certainty.
肯定是我
But in your current situation,
但是你现在这种状态
transferring to another branch
调到代瑞其他的银行
won't be easy for you either.
也不好混
Finding a job elsewhere
去别的地方
is also quite challenging.
工作也不好找
But better than staying here, right?
总比留在这儿强吧
Staying here,
留在这儿
I'll just be the subject of gossip.
被人戳脊梁骨
As long as you're tough enough,
只要你脊梁骨够硬
gossip won't hurt you.
就不怕被别人戳
Do you remember
你还记得在这儿
what I told you in here?
我给你讲过的话吗
Yeah.
记得
You said,
姐说
women
女人
should learn to take care of themselves.
要知道对自己好一点
Exactly.
没错
The workplace has always been
职场一直对女性
tough on women.
都不客气
So we don't need to
所以我们也没有必要
go easy on it.
对职场客气
Working is essential.
工作是立足之本
In times like these,
在这样的时候
the most important thing is
最重要的事情就是
to keep your job.
保住你的饭碗
Got it.
我明白
What others say is their business.
嘴长在别人身上
We shouldn't let it affect us.
别人说什么我们不要管
But I know
但是我会知道
this process will be painful.
这个过程很痛苦
You need to prepare yourself.
你要做好心理准备
[The left side.]
左边
[A bit higher.]
高一点
I said the left side.
我说左边
Raise a little.
左边高一点
Why did they keep it from me?
什么意思啊
When Xiaoning first joined our team,
小涂刚来的时候
she didn't even know how to process a LC.
连信用证都不会办
Who was the one kind enough to guide her?
是谁好心提点她
When she faced challenges at work,
她在工作上受委屈了
who was the one comforting her?
是谁宽慰她
When she and Yuhui
她跟小唐
were competing for performance,
明里暗里争业绩
who was the one having her back?
是谁力挺她
I treated her like a sister,
我把她当妹妹
but what about her?
她呢
What does she see me as?
她把我当什么
A colleague, of course.
当同事啊
What else could it be?
那不然当什么
You two have no blood ties.
你们俩没有血缘关系
And what about Yuheng?
还有老纪
I worked seamlessly
我跟他在工作上
with him.
精妙配合
He points, I follow.
他指哪儿我打哪儿
And those two
他俩
were dating
居然就在我眼皮子底下
right under my nose
谈恋爱
without even telling me.
也不告诉我
You didn't tell them about us either.
你不也没告诉人家吗
The one who hurts me the most is you.
最让我伤心的还是你
We've shared a bed for so long.
我俩同床共枕这么久
I've entrusted you with
我全部的家底
everything I have.
都交给你了
For such a big secret,
你知道这么大的秘密
you didn't even share it with me.
竟然一点风都不透给我
Zhao Fanggang.
赵方刚
Anything that enters
就你这张嘴
your ears
告诉了你
will spread to the whole world.
就相当于告诉了全世界
Are you even aware that
你知不知道
I consider you guys my family,
我把你们当家人
what do you see me as?
你们把我当什么
The biggest fool here is me,
关键我最傻的是
'cause I was the one who tried to
我之前竟然还撮合
set Yuheng up with Yuhui.
老纪跟小唐
I...
我
am the clown in all this.
我才是那个小丑
Anyway,
算了
I'm leaving.
反正我也要走了
Xiaoning is leaving too.
小涂也要走了
The once happy family
原本幸福欢乐的大家庭
is falling apart.
分崩离析了
You and Yuheng
你跟老纪
can rely on each other from now on.
相依为命吧
It's off.
歪了
I rely on Yuheng, sure.
我跟老纪相依为命
Let's go and
那咱俩现在离
get divorced, shall we?
还来得及吗
You told me that
你刚说
Yuheng and I
我跟老纪
could rely on each other.
相依为命
It's chilly today.
今天天气凉
Here, have some hot tea
喝杯热茶
to warm yourself up.
驱驱寒
I've decided
我想好了
to apply for a transfer tomorrow.
明天我就去申请调职
If no other branch is
要是没有别的支行
interested,
接收我
I'm outta here.
我就直接离职
If anyone's leaving,
其实不用的
it
要走
should be me.
也是我走
We had that bet.
我们俩签过对赌协议的
Once you land
你这份
the contract
惟纪的合同
with Weiji,
只要签下来
you'll met the target
带领拓展一部
of doubling the
业绩翻倍的目标
performance.
就达成了
[But I]
我呢
[failed in bringing in]
我还没有拉到
[50 million deposits.]
五千万的存款
Fair's fair.
愿赌服输
I should be leaving.
该走的是我
I know you're
你的工作能力
very capable.
我是了解的
But honestly
但如果就现在这个情况
speaking,
我们客观地去分析
if you left
如果真的是你
section one
离开了拓展一部
or Dairui,
离开了代瑞
it's gonna be
很难找到一个
hard for you to
特别顺心地工作
find a
再说了
satisfying job
这份工作
you love as much.
是你最热爱的
So you can't give up.
所以你不能放弃
It's me who should be leaving.
该走的还是我
Yeah, I got it.
你说的这些我明白
Jing also talked to me about it.
静姐也跟我说过这些
But a deal's a deal.
但是约定就是约定
I can't hold you back
总不能因为我走了以后
just 'cause I might not
找不到更好的工作
find something better.
就让你走吧
And let's face it,
况且我们客观地分析
you earn
在咱们家
several times
你挣的钱
my salary.
比我多好几倍
Ain't fair for
那总没有道理
the big earner to bounce
让挣得多的人走
and the small fry to stick around.
挣得少的人留下吧
You know, I'm all
我是个俗人
about the green,
谁跟钱过不去啊
so it's
所以
best for
我走呢
me, for you,
不管是对我
and
对你
for our family
还是对这个家
if I'm the one to quit.
都是最好的选择
It's not set
现在这件事情
in stone yet.
还没有最终的定论
Let me handle this.
交给我来处理吧
Okay?
好吗
Is there still room for that?
这个约定还有得聊吗
[Time flies,]
这么快
[eight months already.]
八个月就过去了
[This job is]
这份工作
[your true passion.]
是你最热爱的
[So you can't give up.]
所以你不能放弃
[I seem to]
不知不觉
[have fallen deeply]
我好像真的
[in love with my job]
发自内心地喜欢上了
[unconsciously.]
这份工作
[Not for the title]
不是为了转正
[or the security,]
也不是为了稳定
[just]
而是
[love.]
热爱
I used
之前
to get off
每次都在
before the crossing
前面那个路口就下车
and walk to work.
然后自己走到公司去
So it feels a bit strange
今天突然可以坐车
to get a ride
感觉还有点奇怪
with you.
不太适应
Our romance is out in the open,
反正现在也已经公开了
there's nothing to hide.
没什么见不得人的
Before, I felt
以前还老觉得
a little sad and
我们这段关系
guilty about
这么特殊
our
心酸
special situation,
又有点内疚
thinking it'd be
想着有一天
easier
等我们可以
when we are
大方分享的时候
not hiding,
应该这种愧疚感
and I'd feel
就没有了吧
relieved.
会轻松很多
But now, it's not
但是真的到这一刻了
as freeing
怎么一点
as I thought.
都不觉得轻松啊
Mind
要不
dropping me at the next corner?
你还是把我放在前面吧
I wanna take a detour
我想拐个弯
and grab steam buns.
去买包子吃
Really tasty.
那家包子可好吃了
Should I wait for you?
需要我等你吗
Nah.
不用
Go on up.
你先上去吧
One veggie and one meat
帮我拿一个粉丝包
thanks.
一个肉包谢谢
Okay.
好的
Wait.
不好意思啊
Well...
要
Two meat then.
两个肉包吧
Thanks.
谢谢
Xiaoning.
筱柠
What a coincidence!
这么巧啊
I'm sorry that
不好意思啊
when you called yesterday,
昨天你喊我的时候
I was swamped with work
刚好工作上有点急事
and couldn't reply right away.
就没来得及回你
Sorry.
抱歉啊
It's okay.
没事
Tell me,
你跟我讲讲呗
how did you
你跟纪总
meet Mr. Ji?
是怎么认识的呀
He's such a great guy,
这么好的男人
risking himself to
自己都不一定保得全
back you up.
还站出来为你证明
Rare breed.
也太难得了
Talented
又有能力
and responsible.
还有责任心
Why work so hard?
你还拼什么事业啊
Just be
赶紧回家
a housewife,
当全职太太得了
it's way easier than
不比在这儿
working yourself to death here.
累死累活强多了
Yesterday
昨天
he was the creep boss,
他不还是一个
harassing women.
猥亵女员工的老板吗
now you're all praises?
怎么今天就变了呀
And back me up?
什么叫为我证明啊
What do you mean?
什么意思
You didn't see?
你不知道
He put up
纪总亲自
a post on site last night,
在内网发的声明帖呀
with your
还贴了你俩的
wedding pic.
结婚登记照呢
He said you were
昨天晚上就发了
together before
说明了你们两个在一起
he joined S1.
是他来拓展部之前
And he came
况且他来拓展一部
at the boss's request,
也是受行长之请
to save the day.
临危受命吗
So all that
这不就说明
gossip about
之前那些说你在工作中
you using him
勾搭他上位
to get ahead
为了转正
or whatever
不择手段之类的
is bullshit.
都是无稽之谈
Thank you.
谢谢你跟我说这些啊
Hey.
哥
Quitting?
真走啊
Yeah,
你看啊
that's why he's the boss.
领导就是领导
Bold move.
果然霸气
He's giving
那就相当于
those gossipers
直接打了那些说小涂
who accused Xiaoning
什么勾搭上司
of playing dirty
搞职场潜规则
a good slap.
那些人的脸
They hit it off,
人家就是情投意合
got
人家
married
就是
before
奔着结婚去的
working together.
在成为同事之前
Morning.
早
Xiaoning.
小涂
Decided?
你想好了
I don't think Mr. Ji
不过我觉得纪总
will take my resignation.
应该不会收我的辞职信
I'll just give it straight to the president.
我直接递到行长那儿去
Mr Ji.
纪总
Since everyone's here,
正好大家都在啊
I'd like to inform you
我通知大家一项
of a new personnel change.
新的人事变动
The president signed
行长正式批准了
off on my transfer,
我的调职申请
so today's my last day
今天是我最后一天
here.
来这儿上班了
I've already
交接的工作
sorted out the handover stuff.
也都已经汇报给了行里
Tomorrow,
明天
I will
我就正式
leave S1.
离开拓展一部了
I'm the one who should go.
明明该走的人是我
Why quit without telling me?
你为什么要自作主张啊
Did you never
还是说从一开始
care about
你就没有把我们
our deal?
制定的合约当回事
Were you just messing with me?
从一开始就逗着我玩呢
Calm down.
先别生气嘛
It's
其实
my rivalry with S2
是因为我要跟二部竞争
that
才导致
exposed our relation.
我们的关系会曝光
And because
另外也是因为
I joined S1,
我要来拓展一部
you were stressed
你才会每天都提心吊胆
about our relationship
担心着我们关系
being revealed.
会曝光出来
It's all my fault.
整件事情都因我而起
I'll take responsibility.
当然是我来承担了
So from the beginning,
所以从一开始
you signed that bet
你就已经想好了
to keep me from
就是为了不让我多想
worrying too much?
所以才签对赌的
Nope.
说错了
Another thing,
还有一个原因
I wanted you to show
我想让你能够
what you're capable of.
施展你的能力
What am I capable of?
我有什么能力啊
I'm just a regular worker.
我不过就是一个
I'm nobody.
小小的业务经理
But you're
你不一样
the boss's pick.
你是行长派过来的
He'll flip
你这一走
if you leave.
他肯定会生气啊
You know
你也知道
the avoidance
那个金融家属
rule,
回避政策
right?
对不对
To stop
目的就是为了防止
power trips.
利用职权徇私舞弊
You and Xiaoning
你跟小涂呢
aren't married,
虽然没结婚
technically,
严格意义上来说
no rule broken.
不算违规
But mixing work and love
但是你把感情和工作
can be messy,
扯到一块去
it's hard to
就算没违规
clear your name.
它也说不清楚
With her rise
小涂现在发展这么快
and the mess of S2,
又赶上二部出了那个事
rumors
说你呀
fly
利用职权
you're helping
照顾小涂的风言风语
her out.
都已经传出来
Like you said, it's rumors.
您也说了是风言风语
I never misused
我纪昱恒从来就没有
my power.
滥用过任何一次职权
[She got no]
除了人均分配的
[special favors.]
政府存款之外
Only equal deposits
涂筱柠在我这里
quota from the gov.
没有得到过
Nothing else.
任何一次优待
She
转正
earned her
找客户
promotion and clients on her own.
靠的全是她自己的能力
Yes, I understand.
你说的情况我都了解
But she
但小涂呢
really
她
has to leave.
她真的必须得走了
No.
不行
She shouldn't.
涂筱柠她不能走
For her,
这里不仅仅
Dairui is more than
是一个工作的地方
just a company.
对她来说
She's fully invested in for her career.
是她全身心投入的事业
I'm the one who should leave.
该走的人应该是我
Sir.
老师
I'll send
晚些时候
my transfer papers later.
我会把调职申请发给您
Thanks for your
也感谢您一直以来
trust and care.
对我的信任和照顾
[So I told]
所以我就跟
[the president]
我老师说
how capable you are.
你能力很强
If you left,
如果真的是你离开的话
it would
那一定是
be a loss for S1.
拓展一部的损失
[He thought it over]
所以老师想了想
and saw my point,
觉得我说得有道理
so he approved
昨天晚上
my transfer last night.
就批了我的调职申请了
He's not that easy to fool.
行长哪有那么好骗啊
Really?
批了
But
那
where to?
去哪儿呢
I haven't
我市里面
heard of any vacancies
没听说哪个岗位
in the city.
空出来了呀
Could it be demotion?
难道要降级啊
It's Nan'an branch.
是南安县的支行
Still a manager.
继续当经理
Nan'an?
南安县
Over 2 hours away.
开车要两个多小时
Yeah.
是
So far away.
那么远啊
Is this a
这算是
punishment?
惩罚吗
Of course not.
当然不算了
Nan'an branch is a mess,
主要是南安县支行那边
lots of bad loans
积攒了不少的不良贷款
dragging down performance,
常年都压着支行的业绩
ranking the last
去年的时候
in the province last year.
在全省都垫底了
[And managers]
另外客户经理
[have no motivation]
拿不到业绩提成
without bonuses.
他们就没有工作的干劲
It's a vicious cycle.
这成了一个恶性循环
[So the higher-ups]
所以领导们
[want me]
应该是想
[to work there]
让我过去了以后
[and fix it.]
处理一下这件事情
And with all the drama,
另外现在是风口浪尖
sending me away
把我稍微调远一点
keeps me safe.
对我也是一个保护吗
It's
我呢
a good thing,
是去下基层锻炼
grassroots experience.
对我来说是一件好事
Why?
怎么
You'll miss me?
不想让我过去啊
Yeah.
是
It's
下基层
good for experience.
确实可以积攒一些经验
[And staying away]
现在这个时候躲远一点
keeps you out of trouble.
也确实可以避避风头
The president
行长这么做
values you by doing that.
已经算是惜才了
But without this mess,
可是如果没有这些事情
you
你本
should have gone higher.
可以去更好的地方
I'll
我呢
work hard
去了那边
over there.
一定会好好工作
Just a pit stop,
这就是一个过渡
I'll be back soon.
我争取早点调回来
It's so far.
好远呀
Don't worry too much.
别多想了
[Thank you.]
辛苦你了
[I bet]
我猜
[you'll get a better]
你很快会迎来一个
[partner soon.]
更好的伙伴
[See you.]
先走了
Heard you went to HR
听说你下午去了人力
to quit this afternoon.
办了离职啊
There's a
人力那边
new guy in HR,
新来个小伙子
I don't know much about him.
不知道什么情况
[He asked]
他问我说
[if I only work with you,]
在拓展部是不是只认你
and
问我
decided to leave
你要是走了
'cause you're gonna leave.
我是不是也不干了
You won't
那你肯定不会
tell him this, huh?
这么跟他说
You got me.
还是你了解我
I ain't gonna tell them
这个时候我怎么能
I'm loyal to you.
把忠心表给你呢
Gonna make sure they know
我要让所有人都知道
I'm outta here
我的离开
because of Rao Jing!
是因为饶经理
You got it.
还得是你
It's tough for you too, huh?
你也挺不舍的吧
Think
你说
we'll ever be back here?
我们还会回来吗
Your wife's here,
你老婆在这儿
mine here too,
我未婚妻也在这儿
gotta come back.
少不了过来
We're
咱俩
battle bros now.
也算是患难兄弟了
Right.
对了老赵
You just quit,
你是裸辞
got anything new cooking?
新工作有什么眉目吗
Nah.
没有
My buddy's
我朋友那边
got a finance gig
有一家财务公司
needs a short-term AM
需要招短期的客户经理
with 5 years exp.
工作经验需要五年以上
Pay's
薪资报酬
decent.
也还不错
I'll send his info
一会儿我把他名片
to you.
推给你
Might be a good temp thing
如果有需要的话
if you're interested.
去过渡一下
Okay.
好
Thanks.
谢谢
I'm out.
先走了
Don't miss me.
别太想我
Boss!
领导
Hit me up
以后有机会
if something opens up,
随时招呼我
[I'll be in!]
我还跟你干
Anyway,
不管怎么样
Xiaoning's
筱柠这事
drama's over.
可算是落下帷幕了
No more hiding or worries,
她再也不用担惊受怕的
she can date out
可以光明正大地
in the open now.
谈恋爱了
Ji Yuheng is really reliable.
老纪确实靠得住
But why's he
但我不知道这个纪昱恒
holding back?
他还在磨蹭些什么
If it were me,
要是我
I'd marry
我就立马
Xiaoning right away.
拉着筱柠去领证
To tie the knot
在这种狂风暴雨中
amidst all this chaos.
坚定地迈入婚姻的殿堂
That'd be epic.
多有意义啊
Weiyi.
惟依
You said
你不是说
we should go
找个时间
watch the sunrise sometime.
一起去看日出吗
I checked,
我查了一下
Southern Mountain
南山是看日出
is the best spot.
最好的地方
What do you think?
你觉得怎么样
I think
我觉得
it might be packed.
南山人有点多
I'd prefer White Beach.
我想去白沙滩
Why are you up so early?
怎么起那么早啊
It's only 5:30.
这不才五点半吗
You gotta go at 6:00.
你不是六点要出门吗
I wanna
我想给你
pack something for you.
收拾点东西带走
Okay.
就是它了
All set, huh?
带了这么齐
Water, wipes,
水杯湿巾
and socks? Why?
怎么还有袜子
You need
我想着
4 hours
你那边来回路程
for commuting.
就要四个小时
You might drink
那你晚上万一有客户
with clients
需要应酬
at night and
可能喝点酒
not be able to make it back.
就不能赶回来了
So I packed a shirt
给你带了衬衫袜子
and socks just in case.
这些以备不时之需
I also put
车上呢
a blanket in the car
还给你放了个小毯子
for you to nap in
你要是累了
if you're tired.
就在车上小睡一下
You're so thoughtful.
涂小姐这么贴心啊
Thanks.
谢谢
But don't worry,
不过你可以放心
I'll be home,
不到万不得已
unless it's a real emergency.
我是不可能夜不归宿的
Great.
厉害
You passed the test.
考核通过
How long's the gig?
你在那边要待多久呀
Did your
你们领导
boss give you
找你谈话的时候
any hints
有没有说什么
during the talk?
透露一点东西啊
No clue.
还真不好说
Gotta fix
去那边处理完
all the issues
所有的问题
and wait for
还得等市里有位置了
a spot here.
我才能过来
It's
一切
unpredictable.
都很难说
Take it easy.
慢慢来不着急
Forgot to say,
我昨天是不是没跟你说
two newbies joining today.
我们部门要来两个新人
Since you and Fanggang
因为你跟小赵哥
are leaving,
不是走了吗
they're in today.
今天有两个人来报到
The chaos not over yet.
现在风波还没过去
To put it bluntly,
说难听点
I can at least
我去了那边
find some peace there.
还能够躲躲清静
But you might
你这边随时可能
hear some gossip
有一些流言蜚语
or rumors.
有一些闲话什么的
If you do,
真要是听到了
don't let it get to you.
千万别往心里去啊
Just
我这边呢
some gossip.
顶多就是一些闲言碎语
Nothing compared to
跟你在南安县那边
the bad debts
那些坏账比起来
in Nan'an.
那根本都比不了
Take
不着急
your time.
慢慢处理
Life's bumpy,
人生就是这样
full of ups
又不能总在高处
and downs.
都是高低不平的
We'll
现在虽然
ride it out,
我们有困难
slowly but surely,
但慢慢来嘛
things will get better.
以后肯定越来越好的
Got it.
记住了
Where's yours?
你的呢
On the
应该在
bedside?
床头吧
Here.
帮你带上
Xiaoning.
筱柠
Let's take a vacation
等过完这段时间
after this mess.
咱们一起去休假吧
New job, new branch,
你怎么刚上班
and you wanna
就要休年假啊
be off already?
刚去新支行
Okay.
也行
Well.
那
I'll talk to Jing
等忙完这段时间
about it then.
我跟静姐说一下
Here.
来
Your coffee.
咖啡好了
With sugar cube.
加了方糖
Give it a try.
尝尝看
Not bad?
还行